<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Neverblur Blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[Neverblur Blog]]></description><link>https://blog.neverblur.com</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 14:06:50 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[How Online Learning is Failing Millions of Students]]></title><description><![CDATA[The verdict is out. Online learning during Covid has destroyed the future of millions of young students in North America and beyond. Even…]]></description><link>https://blog.neverblur.com/how-online-learning-is-failing-millions-of-students/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.neverblur.com/how-online-learning-is-failing-millions-of-students/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The verdict is out.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online learning during Covid has destroyed the future of millions of young students in North America and beyond. Even after the pandemic comes to a close, the damage might be permanent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some glaring &lt;strong&gt;facts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;61% of students at biggest Independent Student Districts are failing at least 1 subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;51% of surveyed parents reported challenges of learning online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;50% of low-income and 42% of families of colour lack sufficient devices at home to access distance learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Star-ups in Silicon Valley were supposed to help students transition into a new paradigm of education that would democratize opportunity and reduce inefficiencies. In reality, however, things have gotten downhill, real fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Covid 19 has accelerated the education gap by not months, but years. A Mckinsey &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kxii.com/2020/10/13/statistics-show-significantly-higher-failure-rates-for-online-learners-versus-in-person/&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; suggested that students who remain “enrolled could lose 3 to 4 months of learning if they receive average remote instruction, 7 to 11 months with lower-quality remote instruction, and 12 to 14 months if they do not receive any instruction at all.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three core problems that have exacerbated the gap. Let’s take a deep dive into these problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1. Lack of devices&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You would think most students in the US have decent laptops. According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epi.org/publication/the-consequences-of-the-covid-19-pandemic-for-education-performance-and-equity-in-the-united-states-what-can-we-learn-from-pre-pandemic-research-to-inform-relief-recovery-and-rebuilding/&quot;&gt;The Economic Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;, 16% of eighth graders and 25% of poor eighth graders have no desktop or laptop at home. In addition, only about 50% of eighth graders had experience using the device frequently for homework, with a smaller share of poor students (46.4%). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often, students had to share limited devices at home with their family members. Compared to more well off families with multiple devices, their capacity to get school work done were seriously hampered. This led to an overall droppage in class attendance, further exacerbating disparity in academic performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why our partner at Bridging Tech, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9EaX16a8baU&amp;#x26;t=50s&quot;&gt;featured on CNBC&lt;/a&gt;, is busy at work giving affordable devices to homeless students. Mariah Anthony, one of the students that recently received a laptop, used to rely on her old smartphone to study. Imagine typing an essay on her phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we don’t solve the hardware issue fast, no educational policies will ever truly come to fruition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. Lack of internet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can’t study just with laptops. What about broadband?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://edtrust.org/parents-overwhelmingly-concerned-their-children-are-falling-behind-during-school-closures/&quot;&gt;1/4 of parents&lt;/a&gt; who reported having challenges with remote learning reported that they didn’t have reliable high-speed internet access. About &lt;a href=&quot;https://edtrust.org/parents-overwhelmingly-concerned-their-children-are-falling-behind-during-school-closures/&quot;&gt;29% of families of colour and 38% of low-income families&lt;/a&gt; were concerned about access to distance learning because they lacked reliable internet at home. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While online communities like Reddit have a north of 430 million monthly active users, the internet is not as widely distributed among North Americans. What’s worse is that most studies do not consider the “quality” of connections. It is a well known issue that rural areas have significant limitations with broadband access and pricing. Thus, companies like SpaceX are rapidly launching internet satellites to space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pricing is another huge factor. On average, in the US, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/13/20959216/thomas-philippon-economist-interview-internet-access-vergecast&quot;&gt;monthly price of broadband&lt;/a&gt; is $68 per month. The average price in Germany, 35; Japan, 35; Korea 33. All around 30~35 dollars. The reasons behind this absurd pricing of US broadband are complicated, but the price disparity is a serious issue for most low income households.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3. Lack of mental health and communal support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schools have been an integral part of students’ life, giving many a place to belong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever since Covid, students have been suffering from increased mental health issues, leading to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.capecodtimes.com/story/news/2020/12/14/remote-learning-takes-toll-students-mental-health/6543209002/&quot;&gt;higher suicide rates&lt;/a&gt;. According to a recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.capecodtimes.com/story/news/2020/12/14/remote-learning-takes-toll-students-mental-health/6543209002/&quot;&gt;survey via America’s Promise Alliance&lt;/a&gt;, more than “1 in 4 young people reported an increase in lost sleep because of worry, feeling unhappy or depressed, feeling constantly under strain or experiencing a loss of confidence”. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As students’ mental health suffer, their relationships with teachers, basic attendance, and school work suffer. For example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.edweek.org/leadership/opinion-remote-learning-cuts-into-attendance-here-are-remedies/2020/12&quot;&gt;2/3 of teachers surveyed&lt;/a&gt; reported that “assignment-completion rates were down since the start of the pandemic” and “cities including Detroit, Chicago, and Rochester, N.Y., have all reported lower-than-expected attendance rates”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s worsening the situation is that family environments are failing to help students stay on track and look after their mental health. &lt;a href=&quot;https://edtrust.org/parents-overwhelmingly-concerned-their-children-are-falling-behind-during-school-closures/&quot;&gt;For example&lt;/a&gt;, “more than 3 in 4 public school parents reported higher levels of stress. Families earning less than $50,000 annually are experiencing more acute levels of stress – nearly half (47%) of those families report stress levels that are much higher”. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the summary of 3 things that have affected the educational gap during the pandemic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Lack of devices&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;2. Lack of internet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;3. Lack of mental health and communal support&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Education is a compounding system. Without the above infrastructure and support in place, the gap between students’ performance will only accelerate. This will impact admission rates to colleges, life long income levels, and in result, fortify the class divide that rips the economy of the Western world today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start addressing these issues, our partner, Bridging Tech is planning to host a &lt;strong&gt;GoFundMe campaign&lt;/strong&gt; to provide affordable devices to homeless children. If you haven’t already, &lt;strong&gt;sign up for free&lt;/strong&gt; below to get exclusive updates about the campaign and how online learning can become easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;We are Project Neverblur&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neverblur&lt;/strong&gt; is on a mission to increase people’s capacity to learn everyday. We are proud to be working with Stanford’s Bridging Tech to narrow the education gap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe
    src=&quot;https://cdn.forms-content.sg-form.com/4197bc66-6248-11eb-95a5-ee005c614440&quot;
    width=&quot;100%&quot;
    height=&quot;550px&quot;
    style=&quot;border: none;&quot;
/&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>